right the light was doing weird things
I'd restart it and I can't restart it
again so I'm gonna try and keep my head
still is the light hopefully stay
somewhat steady this is my response to
Albert Michael Albert Albert Michael
podcast revolution Z episode 2 entitled
vision ethics matter and so the ethics
he talks about not ethics the values
he's talking about our values that we
generally all can agree on even if we
can't agree on how those are met or what
sis or maybe even rank them as to which
one's the most important to us that any
system that we all can get behind needs
to include all of these things and that
I can get behind so the values he talks
about or equity self management
solidarity diversity and sustainability
and I want to talk about how the global
cooperative we are all going to create
together addresses and deals with all of
these things in a way that doesn't trade
off one for the other so first with with
fairness and equity how much stuff do we
all get and in the system we're creating
together it has to out-compete
capitalism so it's not something the
government isn't gonna come in and give
you your basket of goods that you don't
have to work for it anyway nor are you
gonna have to pull yourself up by your
bootstraps and do everything on your own
we are gonna co-create solutions
together that you get to say what's
working or not working for you you get
to say what you're doing for that
current system what are you doing for
your transportation needs what are you
doing for your food needs and can we
co-create a solution that makes it
better for you makes you spend less
money and time and energy on the system
itself and get more out of it if you're
currently spending 20 hours a week on
food and food preparation working at
your job to pay for groceries and going
grocery shopping and food preparation
and we can offer a system where you
don't have to spend 15 hours a week
doing that that's gonna be a benefit for
you but there's going to be many options
that you get to choose from and if one
of those options doesn't work for you
get to co-create new ones without taking
away from the bigger the bigger group so
self-management this one is really
important to me as an individual I want
autonomy over
my own life I want to be able to have
access to the information I need to make
the decisions and then be able to make
them on my own
and I know in order to have that
information collecting and distributing
both like collective data and our own
data in a way that's that's again you
have no power over your own data so that
you can feel comfortable choosing how
that is used and so it's never about
demanding everyone's going vegan we're
now outlawing this it's about meeting
people where they're at and giving them
the tools to make their own decisions
and if it is in fact ecologically and
health and healthier to go vegan then
people will do that not a coercion but
out of them feeling it in their body and
them having access the information that
shows that that is true so is solidarity
which is mutual and caring relationships
and so clearly not everybody gets along
never are we gonna have everyone get
along but to create tools of peace and
inclusion and I think a big piece of
that is being able to say who you want
to work with and don't want to work with
who who do you live with and who rubs
you the wrong way and being able to
tailor your life and your groups and
your community around people that can
see you for who you are and enjoy being
with you makes life better for everyone
and so curating communities and groups
is part of what we do and creating
mutual and caring relationships involves
under self-management allowing people to
be with who they want but at no point do
we get to kick somebody out completely I
can say I don't want you at my table I
can't say you don't get a table so
diversity this one is that we want a
wide range of options over a narrow
range of options and this is one area
currently that there is a trade-off in
if we have a monopoly there's an
efficiency there there is if we have one
choice if everyone has the same building
we can make that a much cheaper we all
don't want the same building and that's
boring and so finding the trade-off it's
like okay well if you get
if you get the modular housing if we're
dealing with housing it costs you
$10,000 if you want a custom it you know
you're the one choosing to add on to it
if we have a dating site having everyone
on the same dating site it has an
efficiency because everyone's there you
can but if it's only designed for
heterosexual so it's only designed for
monogamy if it's only designed for for
the 90 percent then it's really designed
for nobody because we're all need
somewhere it's like you want to be able
to be your own unique self and find
somebody to matches that you're
compatible with that involves having one
date in sight that is as adaptable and
diverse as possible and so we're
continually looking for ways to make it
work for you and that's part of creating
the system to constantly look for ways
to improve it and to empower people to
bring their voice forward about what's
not working and be given the tools to
create those solutions themselves the
last one though is sustainability and I
mean ecological survival is paramount
right now we're on a planet we're
potentially destroying and none of these
other ones matter if we don't have air
to breathe and water to drink and so
creating a world that works when our
capitalism is destroying our planet and
so giving people access to that
information without demanding they
believe it without saying climate change
is undeniable well clearly it's not
undeniable or people wouldn't be denying
having one place to go for information
that we can agree on the the algorithm
for what makes information true and
accurate not does it agree with me or
not and giving people access to
recreating the means of production in a
sustainable way well we're not mining
from one location with huge
environmental and social impact shipping
it somewhere else to make it so it can
be used for a few days and then thrown
out and never decompose and we can look
at a system design things to last for a
long time to be able to have parts
replaced and have it be nearly
infinitely recyclable we don't destroy
our planet and so it's about again
creating information creating systems
and looking at the truth behind behind
the products we use currently most of
the products use is going to be by
for-profit company
but as we co-create solutions together
we as it makes sense to do so
efficiently when we have the threshold
of people involved to make it work we
are going to recreate the entire means
of production in an efficient
sustainable way so that we're not
destroying the planet and we can
showcase what is happening in the
for-profit companies and demand that
they give us information because we're
their consumers we out-compete them very
easily actually because they have to
make profit for their shareholders we're
taking that same thing that would go to
profit we get to be more efficient
because we don't need marketing Alex
like having a home of the video but will
probably have your search my YouTube
channel that we can create more
efficiently and at the same time we
don't need to put profit to shareholders
we're pretty non profit or that same
resources to purpose instead for
creating a technology and transportation
system we're making decisions on does
this get us to where we need from point
A to point B faster not does it get us
from point A to point B but also what it
does it in first make profit and so we
can co-create a world that gives us
equity self management over our own
lives
solidarity diversity and sustainability
that's today's video please like and
subscribe and comment ask questions tell
me what you want to hear about the goal
of cooperative we are going to create
together